<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>LOGYC Apps</title>
    <link href="https://apps.logyc.xyz/feed.xml" rel="self" />
    <link href="https://apps.logyc.xyz" />
    <updated>2021-03-05T15:59:31+05:30</updated>
    <author>
        <name>LOGYC</name>
    </author>
    <id>https://apps.logyc.xyz</id>

    <entry>
        <title>Onyx Note - Note taking made Easy | LOGYC Apps</title>
        <author>
            <name>LOGYC</name>
        </author>
        <link href="https://apps.logyc.xyz/onyx-note-note-taking-made-easy-or-logyc-apps/"/>
        <id>https://apps.logyc.xyz/onyx-note-note-taking-made-easy-or-logyc-apps/</id>
            <category term="Free"/>

        <updated>2021-03-05T15:59:31+05:30</updated>
            <summary>
                <![CDATA[
                        <img src="https://apps.logyc.xyz/media/posts/1/ps-banner.jpg" alt="" />
                     Evan Patton, lead software engineer for the MIT App Inventor What are your views on the recent increase in&hellip;
                ]]>
            </summary>
        <content type="html">
            <![CDATA[
                    <img src="https://apps.logyc.xyz/media/posts/1/ps-banner.jpg" alt="" />
                
  <p>
    Evan Patton, lead software engineer for the MIT App Inventor 
<br> 
<br>What are your views on the recent increase in the app inventor clones and their future ?
<br>App Inventor is open source so it's great to see others looking to fill gaps in functionality that we have passed up on for one reason or another. I can't really speculate as to the long term viability of any of the downstream distributions as I have no involvement with them, but I do wish them all the best and encourage them to contribute back to App Inventor for the benefit of everyone.
<br> 
<br>How do you see App Inventor and it's distributions like kodular in next 5 years ?
<br>Obviously each distribution has its different priorities. With respect to App Inventor, we have a number of research goals that we are interested. iOS support is the big ticket item we're invested in at a technical level, but we're also doing a lot of research into artificial intelligence and machine learning components. There's also a renewed interest in IOT type applications.
<br> 
<br>Your views on iOS apps development with AI2 ?
<br>We continue to work with Apple App Store Review to get the MIT App Inventor Companion approved for use on iOS. They have more stringent requirements than Google so it's taking more time than I think most folks would like, but we have to play by their rules. We have a couple thousand beta testers using it at this point and it seems to be going fairly well. Internally we're also turning our attention toward the build system and what that will entail from an infrastructure perspective.
<br> 
<br>Can AI2 completely replace Android Studio in future ?
<br>There are fundamental differences between the two platforms that I see no reason one to replace the other. Our aims are mainly at computer science education and empowering people to build apps for change. Android Studio gives much more flexibility but at the cost of additional complexity. There will always be tasks one can do in Android Studio but not in App Inventor.
<br> 
<br>And finally, some tips or suggestions to new young student/users using these platforms.
<br>I think the most important piece of advice I can give is that it's okay to make mistakes. Even professional programmers can introduce bugs into their code (I certainly do), and so when you're learning a new tool or technology you will inevitably make a mistake somewhere along the line. It is expected. I think one of the real benefits of how App Inventor is set up is that you can use the companion app to test frequently and see how your changes affect the behavior of your app. When you encounter a bug, you can try to fix it right then and there by experimenting with changing the blocks. It's an extremely powerful tool to learn from your mistakes and makes you better at the task you're working on.
<br> 
<br>A second important piece of advice I'd give is that through App Inventor you have a great opportunity to use apps to shape the world around you. We've seem some fantastic apps over the years from both young students and adults who have little to no coding experience but see a struggle of a friend or family member and make an impact in their lives. That is an extremely powerful gift. So as you use App Inventor, think about the challenges you see in the world and in your communities and think about how the skills you are learning could be put to use to improve someone's life or the lives of many.
<br>Pavitra Golchha, VP of Inovation Kodular
<br> 
<br> 
<br>What are your views on the recent increase in the app inventor clones and their future ?
<br>As MIT App Inventor is open source, anyone is free to modify and redistribute it, like Kodular did. The recent increase in the clones shows that they want to extend the platform which couldn't made possible with App Inventor itself due to its use of education. And this is good because they spread the message of App Inventor which is enabling everyone to create apps.
<br>How do you see App Inventor and it's distributions like kodular in next 5 years ?
<br> With recent developments like iOS support, I hope that we may be seeing more users trying App Inventor and Kodular (only if that's made open source xD) alike. The App Inventor team has also been working in several more exciting areas like VR, IoT, Alexa, using background tasks, etc. Hopefully, we could see some of these graduate in the next 5 years.
<br>Your views on iOS apps development with AI2 ?
<br>Nowadays, we are in the age of cross-platform apps with Android &amp; iOS being the two leading mobile OS. Cross-platform apps help businesses grow by serving users of both the platforms with a single codebase. iOS support in App Inventor could be revolutionary.
<br>Can AI2 completely replace Android Studio in future ?
<br>No, it won't. While no-code editors brings people of non-technical background on-board, code has its own place. Writing code allows one to achieve a great level of fine-tuning that no-code editors maybe certainly lacking at some point. We can only expect it (no-code editors) to solve a certain level of problems.
<br>Peter Mathijssen, Moderator AI2/Kodular
<br> 
<br>
<br>What are your views on the recent increase in the app inventor clones and their future?
<br>I really think that all the App Inventor clones that are popping up everywhere is a bad thing. A lot of the, sometimes really young, developers only change the interface of App Inventor and think they made another builder are can call themselves developer altogether. We see a number of them stealing code from other builders because they don't understand the concept of copyright. 
<br> 
<br>A lot of those builders already disappeared or are not developed anymore. This will happen over and over again because starting a builder is more than developing the software. You have to have a strong dedicated team and a good plan to make it work. You can see good examples of builders that are succeeding besides App Inventor like Kodular and Thunkable. Builders like Kodular and Thunkable still remember where their roots are and give back to App Inventor in the form of code or advise. 
<br> 
<br>So there are a lot of really small teams trying to compete with each other instead of working together. Users could learn so much by becoming part of the users that contribute to App Inventor. Contribute code, learn how to work together, learn how to write clean code, develop new components, be part of the Google Summer of Code, etc, etc. 
<br> 
<br>How do you see App Inventor and it's distributions like Kodular in next 5 years?
<br>The no-code movement is not going to be stopped, so their importance will become greater and greater. A lot of those builders are payed but builders like App Inventor and Kodular are free to use. Kodular for instance will only charge you if you decide to monetize your app. That is a fair deal I think.
<br> 
<br>Android and iPhone still will be the dominant operating systems on smartphones i think. So tools for writing apps like App Inventor and Kodular will still be around and will take their rightfull place among the other software. Look at for instance what Scratch is doing. In February 2021 it is in 21st place of most popular programming languages according to the TIOBE index. 
<br> 
<br>Your views on iOS apps development with AI2?
<br>Most people in the world use Android phones but from september 2020 there are more then 1 billion active iphone users in the world. App Inventors goal of democratizing software development by empowering all people, especially young people, to move from technology consumption to technology creation will get more meaning if iPhone users will also have the ability to make their own apps.
<br> 
<br>Can AI2 completely replace Android Studio in future?
<br>In theory it could, but i don't think that will happen. What App Inventor also tries to do is to get children interested in programming. Chances are they will switch to other languages after they reach the current limitations of App Inventor.
<br> 
<br>Some tips or suggestions to new young student/users using these platforms.
<br>Take your time to learn. I see users starting with a really big project without knowing the basics of blockly based builders. Start small and then extend your app, piece by piece. Read books/websites, search online, try different methods, view videos, etc, etc. Don't expect to be an expert immediatelly. But above all enjoy and have fun.
<br> 
<br>Taifun, PuraVida Apps
<br> 
<br>What are your views on the recent increase in the app inventor clones and their future ?
<br>generally good… however the market will decide, what happens…
<br>usually people do not like to pay anything to get everything…
<br>new distributions need something to stand out to attract new users…
<br> 
<br>How do you see App Inventor and it’s distributions like kodular in next 5 years ?
<br>MIT App Inventor still will be there, there is MIT behind and as it is open source it will live “forever”…
<br>distributions usually are closed source, so it will depend on the teams… an important part is being able to pay the bills, for example server costs as well as improving the builder, so there must be something to generate income… without that and without a large user base there will be no future for a distribution
<br> 
<br>Can AI2 completely replace Android Studio in future ?
<br>no, blocks will always have their limitations… to have real flexibility you will have to work in Java/Kotlin
<br>Some tips or suggestions to new young student/users using these platforms.
<br>General Tips and Tricks for App Inventor/Kodular
<br> 
<br>Top 5 Tips: How to learn App Inventor or Kodular
<br> 
<br> 
<br>Hope this article helped you to gain some new and Interesting Information, if so then share this to your Family and Friends also.
<br>
<br>Have Questions about this article or another, Join our LOGYC Realm on telegram and ask your doubts.
<br>
<br>
<br>
<br>
<br>
<br>Peace ☮️&nbsp;&nbsp;
  </p>
            ]]>
        </content>
    </entry>
</feed>
